<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-04T08:06:27+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Web Design Agency London | Websites and Landing Pages Design</title><subtitle>Do you need a top-notch Landing Page for your Business? We are the Conversion-focused Landing Page &amp; Web Design Agency in London. We work with business, entrepreneurs and marketers by designing High-Converting Landing Pages, optimised for Lead Generation Optimal User Experience.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Best Webinar Platform</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/best-webinar-platforms" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best Webinar Platform" /><published>2019-05-18T12:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-05-18T12:16:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/best-webinar-platforms</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/best-webinar-platforms">&lt;h5 id=&quot;whats-a-webinar&quot;&gt;What’s a webinar?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Webinar Is Defined As A “Live, Virtual Event That Is Executed Online”. More Specifically, Webinars Are Educational Or Instructive Sessions That Include Both Audio And Visual Communication Between A Speaker And Attendees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Word Webinar Comes From “Web-Based Seminar”, So Webinars Are Basically Digital Seminars That Anyone Can Attend. If You’re Wondering Whether These Webinars Are As Effective As In-Person Events, The Answer Is Yes. With Webinar Software, You Can Share Slides, Interact With Your Audience Through Chat Boxes, And Even Encourage Participants To Raise Questions Using Q&amp;amp;A Features. In Short, Webinar Software Allow You To Mimic Real-Life Seminars To A Tee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-are-webinars-for&quot;&gt;What are webinars for?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies Hold Webinars For A Wide Range Of Reasons, Including:
        Educating Their Target Audience To Generate And Nurture Leads
        Demonstrating Their Product/Service To Potential Customers
        Training Existing Users, And Teaching Them How To Use Their Product/Service&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Analyzing 350,890 Webinars, Gotowebinar Found That Webinars Are Most Popular In The Software And Technology Industry, With 26% Of Webinars Being Produced By This One Industry:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;images/pastedimage.png&quot; alt=&quot;why-we-use-slack.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/h6&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="others" /><summary type="html">What’s a webinar?</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/top-3-reasons-why-we-use-slack.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The complete guide to high-converting landing page design in 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-complete-guide-to-high-converting-landing-page-design" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The complete guide to high-converting landing page design in 2019" /><published>2019-02-15T13:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-02-15T13:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-complete-guide-to-high-converting-landing-page-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-complete-guide-to-high-converting-landing-page-design">&lt;p&gt;A landing page is a web-page which is different from the rest of the pages on the website. A landing page has an objective. Whether it’s capturing contact details or linking to a product page etc. landing pages can use for a variety of actions. I will go through them in detail later.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="cro" /><category term="unbounce-landing-page" /><summary type="html">A landing page is a web-page which is different from the rest of the pages on the website. A landing page has an objective. Whether it’s capturing contact details or linking to a product page etc. landing pages can use for a variety of actions. I will go through them in detail later.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/postsimages/take-away-6th.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Practical Guide to Trello Project Management</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-use-trello-for-project-management" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Practical Guide to Trello Project Management" /><published>2019-01-08T13:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T13:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-use-trello-for-project-management</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-use-trello-for-project-management">&lt;p&gt;Trello is one of our favourite apps. We use Trello to manage projects, our hiring process, and standard operating procedures. We have had our fair share of project/task management apps. Back in the day, we used &lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/basecamp.png&quot; alt=&quot;basecamp.png&quot; /&gt; then moved to &lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/asana.png&quot; alt=&quot;asana.png&quot; /&gt; and we are finally happy and productive using &lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/trello-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;trello-logo.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-trello&quot;&gt;What is Trello?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I assume you are familiar and know the basics of how to use Trello. If you don’t or haven’t used Trello, I would recommend using it or at least trying it. Think of Trello as a big To-Do board where you can define columns to post sticky notes and move them around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/trello.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;trello.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;okay-i-know-trello-whats-butler&quot;&gt;Okay, I know Trello, what’s Butler?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Butler is a Trello add-on which puts your Trello boards on steroids. 
Let me explain by a simple example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you use Trello in a team where you have the following Lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;backlog-to-do-in-progress-test-done-archive&quot;&gt;Backlog, To Do, In Progress, Test, Done, Archive&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now using the basic features in Trello, you can create tasks, assign members and add them to lists. In some instances, you want to attach a member (Sam) to your card when the card is moved to the Test list. Unfortunately, you won’t be able to automate this functionality by just using Trello. So here comes the power of Trello automation using Butler. You can easily add Butler as a member in Trello by tying in Butlerbot when adding a new member.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h4 id=&quot;setting-up-butler&quot;&gt;Setting up Butler&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ol class=&quot;post-list-points&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If not already visible, open the Trello right menu bar by clicking on Show Menu in the  upper right corner of your Trello board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click on Add Members.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type Butlerbot in the search box.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add, authorize and accept T&amp;amp;Cs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You will notice a new list has now been added to your board. This list called ‘Butler Commands’ is a container which stores all Butler commands.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/setting-up-butler.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;setting-up-butler.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Adding your first Butler command&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So from the above example, you can add a Butler command in plain English which says:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighted-points&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When a card is moved into the list &quot;In Test&quot;, add member @sam to the card&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Once you add this command as a card in the new Butler List, Butlerbot will compile it and show a green tick to confirm it understood the command and can run it every time a card is moved into the “In Test” list.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The above command is quite simple but you can come up with complex scenarios which can help you automate a lot of manual actions.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Here is a more complex example:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighted-points&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When a card is moved into list &quot;Development&quot;, add the blue &quot;Development&quot; label to the card, add the &quot;Developer Checklist&quot; checklist to the card, and move the &quot;Developer Checklist&quot; checklist to the top, add the green &quot;In Progress&quot; label to the card, and remove the black &quot;Management&quot; label from the card, and reset checklist &quot;Developer Checklist&quot; on the card.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In the above scenario, we assign a checklist from a template card which we have set up separately.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p class=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/developer-checklist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;developer-checklist.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When a card is moved into the Development List, the Developer checklist is added to the card and moved to the top. Rest of the commands are self-explanatory.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;how-to-archive-trello-cards-automatically&quot;&gt;How to Archive Trello Cards automatically&lt;/h5&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One command which you should always include in your arsenal is the operation cleanup Trello. Every Wednesday at 12:09 BST we archive all cards in Trello which are in the done list for more than 14 days.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;highlighted-points&quot;&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Every Wednesday 12:09 BST, archive all the cards more than 14 days in the list &quot;Done&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;With ButlerBot you can create Standard Operating Procedures (SOP’s) for your various activities like Content Marketing, Social Media, Client Onboarding, Hiring, etc. In our design agency, all our landing page requests are sent to Trello and assigned to a team member. Based on their role the card moves from a Project Coordinator to an Unbounce Landing Page Designer and finally to the client manager. Having a workflow which doesn’t require a manual or documentation means less onboarding and training. We love it when a system just works and we as a business manage processes which manage people.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;We will share our hiring SOP using Trello in future blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="others" /><summary type="html">Trello is one of our favourite apps. We use Trello to manage projects, our hiring process, and standard operating procedures. We have had our fair share of project/task management apps. Back in the day, we used then moved to and we are finally happy and productive using</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/how-to-use-trello.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 is the year of Page Speed and yes, we are ready</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pagespeed-and-load-time-insights-for-websites-and-landingpages" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 is the year of Page Speed and yes, we are ready" /><published>2018-11-14T13:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-14T13:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pagespeed-and-load-time-insights-for-websites-and-landingpages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/pagespeed-and-load-time-insights-for-websites-and-landingpages">&lt;p&gt;Unbounce recently in their latest blog post shared how page load times are going to influence the marketing world in 2019. At Apexure, we have been pushing the boundaries of how to improve page speed and decrease page load times. In this post, I would like to discuss the various routes we undertook and the results. I call them &lt;strong&gt;“1-second landing pages.” or “#1sLP”.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;what-is-a-1-second-landing-page&quot;&gt;What is a 1-Second Landing Page?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A landing page which takes less than a second to load. It does sound very simple from the surface but under the hood, there is some clever stuff set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-can-i-increase-my-page-speed&quot;&gt;How can I increase my page speed?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some factors which can help achieve less than 1-second load time:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--web-host&quot;&gt;- Web Host&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/webhost.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;webhost.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Yes, your hosting provider and their data centre location have a huge impact on load times. This is especially true when you are running PPC or paid traffic campaigns over a geographic location. When we compared highly optimised landing pages hosted on the US vs UK servers for UK audience, the results were quite dramatic. We were able to achieve 0.6 second load times for a landing page hosted in the UK vs 1.0 second when hosted in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--tiny-images&quot;&gt;- Tiny Images&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/tiny.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tiny.jpg&quot; /&gt;
One major sin I find marketers and sometimes content writers do is to upload images over 500kb, sometimes over a megabyte. One basic tool which should be in your arsenal is &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinypng.com/&quot;&gt;Tinypng&lt;/a&gt; You can upload images and get a highly compressed image. Although tinypng or tinyjpg is great, these compressors don’t take into account actual dimensions. They do reduce file size but what if you actually wanted to use the image as a thumbnail? There is still no point in using a 1280x800 image as a      thumbnail. So you need an image and a resize app + an image compressor. You can use Photoshop or an online tool. Once you have resized the image, then compress it and reduce the file size even further.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--sprite-images&quot;&gt;- Sprite Images&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/sprit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sprit.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Do you have icons, badges and other images on your landing pages? Why not combine them into one image and using some clever CSS, swap the image around? This technique reduces the HTTP requests your browser makes every time it needs to load a new resource. So if 100 tiny images are bundled as 1 image, there will be only 1 HTTP request vs 100.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--minified-htmlcssjs-files&quot;&gt;- Minified HTML/CSS/JS files&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/minified.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;minified.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Minifying is the process of removing any whitespace from your code files so the code is compressed. This again saves few KBs of data. Every little helps!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--use-amp&quot;&gt;- Use AMP&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/useAmp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;useAmp.jpg&quot; /&gt;
For mobile campaigns, we would recommend using AMP (Accelerated Mobile Pages). As an early adopter, we currently build all our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/mobile-landing-page/&quot;&gt;mobile landing pages in Unbounce &lt;/a&gt;and love the flexibility of drag ‘n’ drop in an otherwise restricted system.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--use-a-cdn&quot;&gt;- Use a CDN&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/postsimages/usecdn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;usecdn.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Having a host local to your campaign is great, but if you are targeting multiple countries or have dedicated SEO landing pages, I would strongly recommend using a Content Delivery Network (CDN). A CDN maintains a cached version of the images, HTML or any content and stores them in various geographical locations. With CDN, users download data from servers closest to their proximity which improves page speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;dev_tips&quot; class=&quot;dev_tips_custom&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Developer Tips:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;corner_img&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/postsimages/tip.png&quot; alt=&quot;Tips by Senior Web developer&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;blockquote_post_five&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dev_info d-md-flex&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;images/postsimages/sr_webdev.png&quot; alt=&quot;web developer tips&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;dev_name d-inline-block pl-4&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;By Ifrah Bashir&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Senior Web Developer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;dev_tips_list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Defer Parsing Javascript&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Javascript is the main cause of websites loading slowly because when a browser comes across Javascript it executes the script before continuing to load HTML. By deferring parsing of JavaScript means JavaScript(s) should load but only after the content of the website has loaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Avoid Redirects&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redirects are instructions or methods that automatically take visitors of one file to another file or location. Redirects that use the HTTP-equiv=&quot;refresh&quot; attribute or Javascript can introduce even longer waiting times. Google suggests eliminating redirects which are not absolutely necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Use CSS3 and HTML5&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS3 and HTML5 framework is lightweight and designed for speed. When developing custom web pages you should always utilise the latest frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;h5 class=&quot;text-center dev_qoute&quot;&gt;“ The future is speed, are you game? ”&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;section id=&quot;info&quot; class=&quot;info_custom_blog&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Page speed load FAQs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-10 offset-md-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;What is page load time?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Page load time is the time taken to download and show the entire content of a web page in the browser window (measured in seconds). Page load time is an
important web performance metric that directly impacts conversions.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;What is Google PageSpeed Insights?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Google developers have put together an online app which allows web developers to check the performance of their website. You can check the tool at the website.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt; Why is my website slow?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;There could be lots of reasons which could be causing a reduced page load speed. We have discussed some of the main ones in our post above. If you still are facing problems, I would recommend speaking to an expert.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;Is page speed a ranking factor?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;According to Search Engine Land Google has taken into account mobile page speed as a ranking factor in their mobile search results. Since AMP only works for mobile at the moment, Google’s focus is getting mobile users faster results who mostly run on data limited services like 2G or 3G.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;What is a good PageSpeed score?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Rather, than focusing on PageSpeed score, I would recommend reducing the page load times to under a second.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="code" /><summary type="html">Unbounce recently in their latest blog post shared how page load times are going to influence the marketing world in 2019. At Apexure, we have been pushing the boundaries of how to improve page speed and decrease page load times. In this post, I would like to discuss the various routes we undertook and the results. I call them “1-second landing pages.” or “#1sLP”.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/postsimages/factors-which-lead-less-load-time.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Best Website Conversion Optimisation Tactics for Getting More Leads and Enquiries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/conversion-tactics-for-getting-leads" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Best Website Conversion Optimisation Tactics for Getting More Leads and Enquiries" /><published>2018-11-10T13:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-11-10T13:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/conversion-tactics-for-getting-leads</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/conversion-tactics-for-getting-leads">&lt;p&gt;Before we dive into why your website is not converting, you need to ensure your website is set up to track conversions. If you have set up goals in Google analytics, you can skip to the next section. If this is the first time you have read about Goals in Google conversion, then read along.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most straightforward way to track conversions is via Google Analytics. Here is a step-by-step guide to setting up a Google Analytics goal for a Lead Gen form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;1-create-a-thank-you-page-which-links-to-your-main-lead-gen-page&quot;&gt;1. Create a thank you page which links to your main lead gen page.&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you are using a tool like Unbounce or Clickfunnels you can easily create a new page and link it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/thank-you-page-link.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thank-you-page-link.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If you have a Wordpress website you can use various plugins to redirect the user to a thank you page once the form is submitted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-copy-the-thank-you-page-url-and-go-to-your-google-analytics-admin-and-click-goals&quot;&gt;2. Copy the thank you page URL and go to your Google Analytics Admin and click Goals.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/goal-analytics.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goal-analytics.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-create-a-new-goal-and-use-the-url-of-the-thank-you-page&quot;&gt;3. Create a new Goal and use the URL of the thank you page.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/goal-setup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;goal-setup.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a new Goal and use the URL of the thank you page as the destination. Once set you can now track goals/conversions in Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;does-your-call-to-action-button-on-the-website-stand-out&quot;&gt;Does your Call-to-Action button on the website stand out?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a demand to capture users’ attention, you also need to drive them to the next logical step. Whether it’s adding a product to the basket, viewing more info, or downloading an E-book, you need to define action-focused buttons to guide visitors. The buttons on the page should stand out from the rest of the design and should look like actual clickable buttons. Here are some tips which will help you to look at your call-to-action buttons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What stands out gets clicked (call-to-action buttons or links shouldn’t be the same as the rest of your design).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CTA button should create a sense of urgency that guide your visitors towards your goal conversion.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Move your seal or badge closer to the desired action (like the “Place Order” button).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adding directional cues assists in focusing the visitor’s attention on the buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always test the position of your call-to-action button. With simple A/B tests check if the page performs better when the position of the button is on the left, right or middle of the section.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;do-you-have-a-low-traffic-website&quot;&gt;Do you have a low traffic website?&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Low traffic means a low number of conversions. Even with an optimised website, you can’t expect all visitors to fill out a form or buy a product. However, what you can do is increase your traffic from hundreds to tens of thousands of visitors.  Traffic can be increased by:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--paid-ads&quot;&gt;- Paid Ads&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/paid-ads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;paid-ads.jpg&quot; /&gt;
This is a no-brainer. The more money you spend on Google and Facebook ads the more traffic you will generate. As this can easily burn a hole in your marketing spend, its best to use paid traffic as only one of your traffic channels.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--seo&quot;&gt;- SEO&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/seo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;seo.jpg&quot; /&gt;
Using Search Engine Optimisation you can build traffic for free. Although it’s free traffic, you will have still invest time, money and effort in getting indexed in Google. SEO techniques such as off-page (link building) and on-page (optimising web pages so search engines can rank it) are difficult to master as Google changes search algorithms quite frequently. However, nothing is impossible and with effort and perseverance comes reward.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;h5 id=&quot;--content-marketing&quot;&gt;- Content Marketing&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/content-marketing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;content-marketing.jpg&quot; /&gt;
An ecosystem which puts your brand in front of your target audience. By using tools such as blogs, podcasts and YouTube you can increase awareness and generate traffic. I will strongly recommend checking out Content Machine in which Dan Norris the author used Content Marketing to Build a 7-figure Business With Zero Advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;do-visitors-trust-your-brand-when-they-visit-your-website&quot;&gt;Do visitors trust your brand, when they visit your website?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a study by Econsultancy, physical address, contact phone number, and email address are the top three credibility signals for any website. Clearly displayed contact details subconsciously assures users that there is a real business behind a website. One of the best ways to add contact details is to incorporate an effective contact us page within your website. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/contact-us/&quot;&gt;contact us page&lt;/a&gt; is an integral part of a website allowing users - the customers, investors, or perhaps advertisers - to get in contact with you. As a business owner, having a contact us page converts users into &lt;a href=&quot;apexure.com/lead-capture-page-template/&quot;&gt;leads for your business&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;best-practices-to-follow-while-creating-your-contact-us-page&quot;&gt;Best practices to follow while creating your contact us page:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;best_practice&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;1. Use everyday language&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep your writing simple, use terms that can be easily recognised by your visitors. The three most widely used words are “Support,” “Help” and “Contact Us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;2. Avoid grammatical errors&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even small grammatical errors can make a negative impression on your visitors. Double check your contact page before publishing it on your website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;3. Make it easy to find&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Links to the contact page should appear in the header or the footer of the website. You should always make the contact link easier to find on the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;4. Make it look good&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never underestimate the power of a visually appealing contact page. While the page may be simple, careful thought must still go into its design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;5. Make it mobile Responsive&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the number of people using mobile devices to access the web has surpassed desktop users, make sure your contact page looks good on all mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;6. Add a Google map&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adding a Google map on your Contact Us page helps visitors easily enter the Google interface and request directions directly from their home/office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;7. Add Privacy Policy Details&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-GDPR, make it easier to find and view Privacy Policy details across your site. Especially when asking for contact info from your visitors, have a simple yet solid optin-message so visitors are not left in any doubt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;best_practice_inner&quot;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;8. Increase Trust&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can reinforce trust by showcasing testimonials, reviews or partners logos on your contact us pages. Social proof or any trust signal will nudge the visitors to fill out the form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
I will be writing more on how you can [increase conversions from your websites ](https://www.apexure.com/wordpress-web-design)and landing pages. I hope you found this post useful. If you have any tips of your own, would you mind sharing them with our readers?
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section id=&quot;info&quot; class=&quot;info_custom_blog&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;Some Questions On CRO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col-md-10 offset-md-1&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;How do you calculate the conversion rate?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;The conversion rate is calculated by simply diving the number of conversions by the number of total clicks. For example, if you had 20 conversions from 100 clicks, then your conversion rate  would be 20%, since 20 ÷ 100 = 20%&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;What is a conversion on a website?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Conversion could mean different things. Typically a conversion is when a user submits a form on the website or purchases a product. However, in some instances, a conversion could also mean a user clicked a button and viewed the next page in the online sales funnel.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;Why is Conversion Rate Optimization Important?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Optimising conversion rate can have a significant impact. Let's consider this scenario where a business spends £1,000 on Google Ads and generates 100 leads at a conversion rate of 5%. The Cost Per Lead is £10.
Now with CRO lets assume we increase the conversion rate to 7% which means 140 leads which imply we reduced the Cost per Lead to £7.14. The business can continue spending the same amount of budget and enjoy more leads or reduce the budget.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt; How do you increase conversion rate?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;Increasing conversions can be achieved by split testing. In a split test, we can create 2 variations of the same page. We call the first variation as control and in the other variation we add a change. E.g. we change the colour of the button from red to orange. By sending the same volume of traffic to each variant we can calculate which variation performs better over time. &lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;question_warapper&quot;&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;&lt;span&gt;Q.&lt;/span&gt;What is the average conversion rate?&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;h6&gt;&lt;span&gt;A.&lt;/span&gt;There is no fixed answer for it. Unbounce did a study by testing landing page results across various industry verticals you can check the results here.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/conversion-unbounce.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;conversion-unbounce&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="cro" /><summary type="html">Before we dive into why your website is not converting, you need to ensure your website is set up to track conversions. If you have set up goals in Google analytics, you can skip to the next section. If this is the first time you have read about Goals in Google conversion, then read along.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/images/get-more-leads-takeaway-image.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The 10 best core company values and why you need them in your organisation</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/organisational-core-values" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 10 best core company values and why you need them in your organisation" /><published>2018-10-13T13:04:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-13T13:04:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/organisational-core-values</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/organisational-core-values">&lt;p&gt;I must admit that the knowledge and implementation of core values for me personally has been a challenge. During the inception of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/unbounce-landing-page-designer/&quot;&gt;design agency&lt;/a&gt;, we didn’t have a set of guidelines or organisational core values. Like most entrepreneurs, my days were spent on firefighting issues, chasing shiny objects, answering support queries and busy with normal activities. That’s when I realised I needed help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The awakening, as I would call it, happened when I stumbled upon the book ‘Delivering Happiness’ by Tony Hsieh. I would instead call the book - The adventures of Tony Hsieh. I enjoyed listening to the audiobook over my commute from Wembley Park to London Bridge on the busy London underground.  With my headphones on and oblivious to my fellow passengers, hearing Tony narrate the book himself was fresh, exciting and engaging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the book I had no clue of Tony or Zappos (Zappos is an online e-commerce store based in the US, which got acquired by Amazon in 2009 for $1.2Billion). I picked it after browsing the recommended &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/ebook-landing-page/&quot;&gt;book category&lt;/a&gt;. I was looking for a reference in the business category but had no idea what was in store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over a period of two weeks, I completed the audiobook, and since I enjoyed it greatly, I listened to it again. Hearing Tony’s story opened up my mind; It was clear I had to spend time building the core values of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/web-design-essex-london&quot;&gt;agency&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t read/heard the book, I would highly recommend it and won’t spoil it for you. In a nutshell, Zappos is known for its fantastic customer support and is considered one of the best workplaces in the world. You can also read up on their culture book to learn more about their ethos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it was my turn. I wanted to create a similar culture book, one which outlined our vision and ethos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the process I took in creating the core values of our organisation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;1-write-my-vision-and-values-of-the-business&quot;&gt;1. Write my vision and values of the business&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/vision-and-values-of-the-business.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;vision-and-values-of-the-business.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a company leader, I went ahead and started to put together what became the first draft of our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/web-design-essex-london&quot;&gt;company culture&lt;/a&gt;. The first draft was lengthy and included a range of information from on how to treat customers to how to help others in the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;2-get-everybody-involved&quot;&gt;2. Get everybody involved&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/get-everybody-involved.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;get-everybody-involved.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realised that rather than dictating my version of organisational core values and asking everybody in the team to opt-in, that having everyone write their version of the own core values was better. It was inspiring as I went through each submission as I realised we had a lot of shared values. Now it was time to organise them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;3-group-and-order&quot;&gt;3. Group and Order&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/group-and-order.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;group-and-order.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we had everything arranged, we then voted and grouped the top 10 values. On finalising the top 10 values, we solidified them as our core values and shared them across the team. The core values are now part of our employee onboarding and have become the first page on our internal company wiki.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every year we revisit our core values and revise it accordingly.  Now, to answer the topic of today’s discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h5 id=&quot;why-are-core-values-important-to-an-organisation&quot;&gt;Why are core values important to an organisation?&lt;/h5&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Core values not only define the blueprint of how people should work and act not just in the workplace but also bring those values into their day to day lives
If you are a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/our-team/&quot;&gt;company leader&lt;/a&gt; or running an early start-up, the following list will help to summarise on why you need core values in your company:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Organisational Core values give purpose and describe the ‘Why’ of the business. It’s like a moral compass which aligns everyone to a joint mission.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Core values set a benchmark; a legacy which stands out the test of time. If job candidates are not happy with your core values chances are they are not a good fit for the company.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Core values set a standard and help the business align, especially in difficult and challenging times.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to receive a copy of our organisational core values, please send me an email on &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:waseem@apexure.com&quot;&gt;waseem@apexure.com&lt;/a&gt;, and I will be happy to share it with you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="others" /><summary type="html">I must admit that the knowledge and implementation of core values for me personally has been a challenge. During the inception of our design agency, we didn’t have a set of guidelines or organisational core values. Like most entrepreneurs, my days were spent on firefighting issues, chasing shiny objects, answering support queries and busy with normal activities. That’s when I realised I needed help.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/core-values-and-why-you-need-them-in-your-company.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Top 3 reasons why we use slack and not email in our marketing agency</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-3-reasons-why-we-use-slack" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Top 3 reasons why we use slack and not email in our marketing agency" /><published>2018-10-09T12:16:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-10-09T12:16:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/top-3-reasons-why-we-use-slack</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/top-3-reasons-why-we-use-slack">&lt;p&gt;In our early days back in 2007 I started looking for an app which could improve our communication, help us collaborate and add some fun&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon Campfire, although pricey we gave it a shot. Campfire was fun, but as our team was growing, we soon found we needed a more dedicated app for communication. After a quick google search, hipchat popped up. I was thrilled, Hipchat looked promising. Our whole team of 10 adapted to hipchat quickly and found ourselves hooked.  Hipchat was fun, and we used it as part of our daily communication. As a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/web-design-essex-london&quot;&gt;landing page agency&lt;/a&gt;, we had many assets to send around, and hipchat replaced our email. We were quite happy with hipchat and soon found a new kid on the block. Slack mostly attracted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/saas-landing-page/&quot;&gt;SaaS companies&lt;/a&gt; and disrupted the marketplace. I remember the first time I heard about it was at an event when the organisers shared their slack channel with the participants. Something was different, and I felt the pain we endured has somehow replaced with some cool words. Because I was a happy customer and pretty much satisfied, I didn’t want our team to switch over…yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started when I was invited to join a Slack Team. I was working as a contractor and invited by the CEO. Straight away I saw channels, hashtags, gifs, emojis. This felt like a different world. Cleaner, great User interface and the most important bit - it worked. Its strange over the years, when I first used Skype (which almost dominated the marketplace) turned out to be a complete failure and lost its market. Now I use Skype to either speak to family members who still have a desktop or with some connections who don’t want to adapt. However, I want to focus on slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For most of you, slack might be your first team chat app and to understand why it has taken over team communication is down to 3 things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;1-platform-independent&quot;&gt;1. Platform Independent&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-we-use-slack.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;why-we-use-slack.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been a Mac user since 2007 and our remote team mostly devs used Windows. This created a problem in itself. Not many apps could talk to each other. Tools like Dropbox disrupted the file-sharing market and created a tool which shared files across various platforms, operating systems, devices. I would compare Dropbox to slack. Slack exactly did that. I now use slack on my iPhone, some of our team members use slack on Chrome while some have slack installed on their Windows machine. It works seamlessly and syncs across, technology at its best. As a user I don’t have to care or worry about how it works, it just does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;2-great-user-experience&quot;&gt;2. Great User Experience&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-we-use-slack-great-user-experience.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;why-we-use-slack-great-user-experience.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from a design background, I love the attention to detail. Slack is packed with tiny little details which collectively makes it a great product. The fact you can customise welcome quotes when slack loads up show how the team has thought of tiny little details to delight team members and create great user experience to make the product stick! Also as a sidenote slack looks pretty great. Coming from white and grey interfaces, Slack added the dark theme, which looks excellent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;3-reliability&quot;&gt;3. Reliability&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/uploads/why-we-use-slack-reliability.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;why-we-use-slack-reliability.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a user you want things to work. Slack is not perfect; it does crash once in a while. However, the way it gracefully responds to broken wi-fi or potential errors adds to the excellent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/unbounce-landing-page-designer/&quot;&gt;user experience&lt;/a&gt;. Tools like Skype running for decades still are no match to Slack on reliability. We never had problems where team members didn’t get messages or file were blocked, slack crashed etc. These words will resonate well with users pre-slack days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To conclude, as an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apexure.com/web-design-essex-london&quot;&gt;agency&lt;/a&gt; we love slack and use it on an hourly basis. Slack removes friction and helps us be more productive. In our agency, we surround ourselves with great products so we can inspire ourselves and help change the world. Do you use slack at your workplace, what do you like about it the most?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Waseem Bashir</name></author><category term="others" /><summary type="html">In our early days back in 2007 I started looking for an app which could improve our communication, help us collaborate and add some fun</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/uploads/top-3-reasons-why-we-use-slack.jpg" /></entry></feed>